Contact

farhaj.ahmed10@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/farhajahmed (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

С

Swift

iOS Development

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Social Media Marketing Certification
Certificate of Appreciation for serving
as a mentor for Karachi Code
Content Marketing

Honors-Awards

Vice Chancellor's List Dean's Honor List Dean's Honor List Dean's Honor List

Farhaj Ahmed

Software Engineer - iOS @ Hudasoft Pakistan

Summary

Currently, a Software Engineer - iOS at Hudasoft Inc. Previously, worked as an Assistant Project Manager at CEE Solutions Private Limited and iOS Engineer at Time Based Software, LLC with 2.5+ years of experience in iOS Native Application Development and also, a teammate of Swift Pakistan Developer's Community.

Within the past few years, I trained undergraduate students and professionals for iOS Application Development at Zeal International Training Center. Furthermore, conducted iOS training and workshops at well-reputed universities in Pakistan and now, have my own YouTube channel to create up-to-date tech education content for people for free. Besides training for iOS App development, I create meaningful content related to self-development, business, and startup development.

As for recent qualifications, I graduated last year with an MBA in Marketing from the Institute of Business Administration, Karachi.

You can find me on YouTube at http://www.youtube.com/c/ FarhajAhmed

Experience

Texas, United States

Hudasoft Software Engineer - iOS February 2022 - Present (2 months)

- · Recommend changes and feature enhancements

· Write clean and efficient codes for iOS applications

- Manage the entire application lifecycle from concept to design, testing, release, and support
- Maintain the code with new coding practices, modern design patterns, and mobile technology trends

- Identify potential problems and resolve application bottlenecks
- Fix application bugs before the final release
- Collaborate with the design team to define app features
- Ensure quality and performance of the application to specifications
- Publish application on App Store
- Maintain and optimize the code of the application as per the Swift Style Guide
- Troubleshoot to ensure the code is concise, clean, reusable, and secure

CEE Solutions (Pvt) Ltd Assistant Project Manager June 2021 - February 2022 (9 months)

Karachi Division, Pakistan

I was responsible for the management of internal and external projects while also managing the marketing of the organization.

My core responsibilities were:

- · Managing project progress and adapting work as required
- Preparing project proposal, business requirements, and software specification documents for all the projects
- Meeting clients and gathering requirements to guide the development team
- Managing relationships with clients and stakeholders
- Overseeing all incoming and outgoing project documentation
- Developing project plans for digital marketing and enterprise application tracks
- Assigning and delegating work to the development team
- Client coordination and communication
- Managing a small team of project coordinators
- Maintaining a talent pool for smooth operations

DigiPAKISTAN - National Skills Development Initiative iOS Lead Trainer
May 2021 - December 2021 (8 months)

Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan

DigiPAKISTAN National Skills Development Program is an IT initiative launched with the vision of Pakistan's digital ambition and to work towards a digitally progressive and inclusive Pakistan. I'm appointed here as an iOS Lead Trainer to train and conduct online classes for the youth of Pakistan related to iOS Development. I create and upload up-to-date iOS Development Training Content in Urdu and Hindi.

Zeal International Training Center

iOS Trainer

December 2019 - March 2021 (1 year 4 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

I was responsible for creating and updating course content for iOS

Development. I have prepared international standard training content to train students for iOS Native Application Development. In addition to this, I also did social media marketing to promote the course online. I have conducted online and on-site training sessions. I have trained a total of four batches under ZITC. For the batches that I trained, 30+ undergraduate students and professionals got job and internship offers from local and international tech firms.

NGOgo

Product Management Trainee

June 2020 - August 2020 (3 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

- Assigned several tasks related to understanding different customer segments for the digital product.
- Conducted interviews and built presentations to summarize my findings.
- Recommended several product features to the product development team to improvise user experience of the digital product
- Divided customers into groups to market for digital products
- · Presented findings, obtained from interviews

Time Based Software, LLC iOS Engineer

February 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 11 months)

Karachi, Pakistan

- Developed iOS Version of Potluck App: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ potluck-party/id1352816101
- Checked for the quality and responsiveness of applications
- Debugged and improved application performance
- Assisted in maintaining code quality and its organization
- Engaged with the team to define, design, and ship new features
- Interviewed candidates for the development team

Education

Institute of Business Administration

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Marketing · (2019 - 2021)

DHA Suffa University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science · (2013 - 2016)